John Seabury Flyers and Posters ARC.0065
Library and Archives
John Seabury Flyers and Posters
Bulk, 1988-2011
1980, 1988-2011
ARC.0065
Library and Archives
4.07 Linear feet (1 shared half hollinger box, 1 shared flat file drawer)
The John Seabury Flyers and Posters collection spans the years 1980 and 1988 to 2011. The collection consists of 26 concert posters for various bands and venues, one poster for the Jean-Luc Godard film Sympathy for the Devil, and 19 concert flyers, mostly from shows at Slim's in San Francisco--all created by John Seabury. Bands featured in this collection include Adam Ant, George Clinton, The Damned, John Doe, Mars Volta, Megadeath, Willie Nelson, Pavement, Psychotic Pineapple, Queens of the Stone Age, Radiohead, The Rolling Stones, Todd Rundgren, The Tubes, and Rob Zombie. The collection provides a sampling of Seabury's artistic work for various bands and concerts in the United States and Europe. Seen in a broader context, the collection provides insight into how mainstream and alternative rock bands and venues promoted their shows during the 1980s-2000s and provides reference for the artists that played during that era.
Seabury, John
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Patrons must sign the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibility and Privacy Rights statement on the Researcher Registration form before using this collection. Consult the Library and Archives in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
Related Archival Materials note
Related materials providing content on the Cleveland Agora Theatre and Odeon Concert Club may be found in other collections that constitute a part of the Northeast Ohio Popular Music Archives.
Custodial History note
The John Seabury Flyers and Posters were received by the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum as a gift from John Seabury on April 1, 2010 and April 27, 2011.
Biographical Note
John Seabury is an artist, graphic artist, comic illustrator, and musician located in Oakland, California. Seabury attended the San Franciso Art Institute from 1974-1977 and has been a freelance illustrator and designer for countless publications and record labels since the mid-1970s. He uses traditional techniques, such as pen and ink, scratchboard, watercolor, silkscreen, collage, etching, and lithography, plus modern digital techniques.
In 1995, Seabury began designing and producing limited edition silkscreen concert posters for various bands and performers, including George Clinton, Devo, Megadeath, Willie Nelson, Queens of the Stone Age, Radiohead, and Todd Rundgren.
His artwork can be found in two books: The Art of Rock (Abbeville Press, 1987) and The Art of Modern Rock (Chronicle Publications, 2002).
Sources
“John Seabury - Illustrator - Berkeley.” Creative Hotlist. Accessed March 17, 2011. http://www.creativehotlist.com/index.asp?linkTarget=fullProfile.asp&indID=159820.
“Eclectix Interview 15: John Seabury.” Eclectix Etc. Accessed March 17, 2011. http://web.mac.com/eclectixp/Eclectix/eclectix_etc./Entries/2011/1/4_Eclectix_Interview_15%3A_John_Seabury.html.
Scope and Contents
The John Seabury Flyers and Posters collection is arranged into two series by type: flyers and posters, and then chronologically.
Agora Theatre and Ballroom (Cleveland, Ohio); Ant, Adam; Clinton, George, 1940-; Damned (Musical group); Godard, Jean Luc, 1930-; Megadeth. (Musical group); Nelson, Willie, 1933-; Northeast Ohio Popular Music Archives; Odeon Concert Club (Cleveland, Ohio); Pavement (Musical group); Psycotic Pineapple (Musical group); Queens of the Stone Age; Radiohead (Musical group); Rolling Stones; Seabury, John; Zombie, Rob, 1966-; Alternative rock music; Film posters; Graphic artists; Heavy metal (Music); Posters; Printed ephemera; Rock concerts; Rock music--Posters
- Series I: Flyers, 1980, 1989-1992
  Scope and Contents
  Contains 19 concert flyers created by graphic artist John Seabury. All but one of the flyers are for concerts held at Slim's in San Francisco, California. Performers include Camper Van Beethoven, Dick Dale, John Doe, Four Non-Blondes, Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Psycotic Pineapple, and The Ultras. The flyers are arranged chronologically.
  - Psycotic Pineapple, 1980 August 4-1980 September 15; 7.75" x 14" (Box-folder 1-1, Object 1)
  - Winter Surf Stomp!: Square Roots, Trebels, Let's Go Bowling, 1989 January 13 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 2)
  - Pearl Harbor, Rhythm Riot, Ed Haynes, 1989 February 7 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 3)
  - Hellhounds, Kingsound, Ramblers, 1989 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 4)
  - Hawkins, Screamin' Jay, Universal Congress Of, Po Go Bo, 1989 March 31 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 5)
  - de Forest, Carmaig, Sneetches, Genuine Diamelles, 1989 April 11 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 6)
  - Blazing Redheads, Timmie Helsa and the Converse All-Stars, 1989 July 20 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 7)
  - Camper van Beethoven, Souled American, Movie Stars, Black Sun Ensemble, Sextants, 1989 July 21-1989 July 22 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 8)
  - Hangmen, Maximillian's Motorcycle Club, Sextants, 1989 August 22 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 9)
  - Birdkillers, Flophouse, Cement Trampoline, 1989 August 29 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 10)
  - Lunch, Lydia, Wanda Coleman, Don Bajema, Eugene Robinson, 1990 March 11 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 11)
  - World Entertainment War, Eskimo, 1990 July 29 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 12)
  - Doe, John, Kimm Rogers, 1990 August 6 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 13)
  - Ultras, Crazy 8's, World Entertainment, 1990 August 24 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 14)
  - Movie Stars, Harm Farm, Josef Brinckman and the Conspiracy of Equals, 1990 November 6 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 15)
  - Four Non-Blondes, Capture the Flag, Snakewalk, Havalinas, Fisherman, 1990 November 8, 1990 November 11 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 16)
  - Doe, John, Steve Young, Nancie DeRoss, Marti Jones and Don Dixon, 1991 February 19, 1991 February 26 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 17)
  - Beat Farmers, Skankin' Pickle, Little Women, Bourdon Deluxe, 1991 March 21, 1991 March 24 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 18)
  - Ultras with Dick Dale, 1992 August 1 (Box-folder 1-1, Object 19)
- Series II: Posters, 1980, 1988-2011
  Series II: Posters contains 25 concert posters and one film poster created by graphic artist John Seabury. Performers include Adam Ant, George Clinton, The Damned, Mars Volta, Megadeath, Moonalice, Willie Nelson, Pavement, Queens of the Stone Age, Radiohead, The Rolling Stones, Todd Rundgren, The Tubes, and Rob Zombie. The posters are arranged chronologically.
  - Psychotic Pineapple, 1980; 23" x 29" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 1)
    Limited Print Run
    Non-numbered edition of 200
  - Crime, Psychotic Pineapple, 1988 August 28; 17" x 11" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 2)
  - Richman, Jonathan, Noe Valley Ministry, 1995 April 21-1995 April 22; 29" x 23.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 3)
    General note
    Artist Proof
  - Pavement at the Cleveland Agora, 1995 May 19; 23" x 29" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 4)
    224/350
  - Ant, Adam, Dwellers at the Odeon Concert Club, 1995 May 23; 29" x 23.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 5)
    319/450
  - Radiohead, 1995 July 13; 29" x 23" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 6)
    220/300
  - Rundgren, Todd, Lucy Lee, 1995 August 9; 26" x 14.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 7)
    189/225
  - Temporary Insanity: A Poster and Comix Show, 1996 June 15-1996 June 16; 26.25" x 18" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 8)
    199/200 - signed by artists Gary Grimshaw and John Seabury
  - Psycotic Pineapple, Sudden Fun, 1996 November 12; 22.5" x 18" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 9)
    183/250
  - Lunachicks, Altar Boys, Auntie Christ, 1997 May 22; 20" x 26" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 10)
    167/250
  - Pynotics, 1999; 12" x 9" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 11)
  - Mr. Bungle, Melvins, No Means No, Kids of Widney High, Fantômas, 1999 December 31-2000 January 1; 35" x 22.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 12)
    235/1000
  - Built to Spill, Creeper Lagoon, 2000 June 29-2000 July 1; 24" x 17.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 13)
    271/300
  - Clinton, George and Parliament Funkadelic, Club Townshend, 2002 May 7; 22.5" x 13.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 14)
    130/300
  - Tubes, X-Rated Porno Machine, 2006 September 2; 22.5" x 15.5"; ChormaDepth 3D image with required glass for viewing (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 15)
    100/200
  - Nelson, Willie and family, 2007 April 16; 19" x 12" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 16)
  - Megadeath, 2008 February 14; 24" x 18" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 17)
    282/300
  - Queens of the Stone Age, 2008 March 1; 19.75" x 13.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 18)
    26/39
  - Sympathy For the Devil, 2009 April 3; 18" x 40" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 19)
    Non-numbered edition of 175
  - Fucked Up, 2009 April 8; 21.75" x 13.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 20)
    51/110
  - Mars Volta, 2009 July 8; 17.25" x 12.75" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 21)
    190/200
  - Deep, 2009 August 6; 24.75" x 13.75" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 22)
    88/100
  - Moonalice, 2010 August 29; 12.75" x 17.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 23)
  - Damned, 2010 February 14; 15.75" x 21.5" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 24)
    89/125
  - Zombie, Rob, Catalyst, 2011 February 6; 17" x 12" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 25)
    169/300
  - Moonalice, 2011 April 2; 12.75" x 17.25" (Drawer-folder FF.1.4-7, Object 26)